"Renaissance" means "rebirth" and one rediscovered the ideal of antiquity-
-When you thought had been forgotten during the dark Middle Ages.
Renaissance is a restoration or look back to the ever-
-In this case to antiquity.
You want to return to what you thought of as the cradle of civilization.
You not only rediscover the old one but also discover new things.
Europeans are going for them new parts of the world-
-while you conquer and colonize-
-And you look out for the first time into space.
Nearly one -third of Europe's population dies in the deaths.
Everyday life was for most people just like before.
They lived mainly as a farmer.
They followed this year's bicycle quite a lot with the seasons-
-And devoted itself to sowing and harvesting.
As the Center for the Renaissance you usually place Italy and Florence.
During the 1300s, the ideas and ideals of the Renaissance are emerging here.
From there they spread across Europe, sometimes quite slowly.
In Sweden, it takes two hundred years before the thoughts are attached.
It is the individual, not God, who is to be at the center.
You pay tribute to the creative ability and we get the concept of "Renaissance man"--
-The someone who is good at several different things.
One stops seeing artists as craftsmen-
-and start talking about creative geniuses.
The new human view and ideals are picked up by the rulers.
It contributes to challenging the power of the church.
Now Reformation-
-The church is divided into a Catholic and a Protestant part.
Previously, they had a uniform view of religion.
There was a church that had been around for a long time.
The split allows one to question religious truths.
The Renaissance man does not want to think about life after this, as in the Middle Ages.
Almost everything from the Middle Ages is seen as goofy.
-and in rusty armor he makes a confused journey in Spain-
-with his gunman Sancho Panza.
He is looking for adventure and evil to fight-
-But there will only be developments and trouble against imagined enemies.
He goes to attack on windmills, in the belief that they are giant-
-What he finally returns home.
There he falls asleep.
When he wakes up, he realizes that he has behaved snapped.
Don Quijote is crazy, that thing is clear.
But who is not crazy?
That's what I think is one of the great features-
"When Don Quijote saw them, he said to his armor:"
"'Happiness leads us better than we could wish.' '
"'Just look, dear Sancho, there are thirty hideous giants'"-
-"'that I will trap the last man.'"
"'With the change we base our wealth. It is a godly pleasant deed' '--
-'' to eradicate the rice from the world's surface. ''
"'What giants?'
Sancho wondered. ”
The language of "Don Quijote" feels pretty old-fashioned
-With many old words and concepts, but you immediately notice that it is comedy.
The narrative voice has its own views-
-And jokes at Don Quijote's expense.
The action is quite easy to understand.
There are no difficulties.
Shakespeare wrote many well -known pieces.
They can be divided into four categories.
Comedies: Stories with happy ending.
Tragedies: where it ends unhappily, as for these two.
They die.
Historical dramas, which are based on things that have happened ...
... and sago games, which have the sagas and are more dreamy.
One reason for his popularity is that he creates complex characters.
They often wrestle with internal conflicts and do things that they later regret.
They are very human - just like you and me.
I could shut myself in a nutskal-
-and feel like king over infinite space-
-If I didn't have such nasty dreams.
It is so easy to recognize in what he writes om-
-And how he describes people, behaviors, relationships and meetings.
It must be themselves "it" with him, that there is life in the texts-
-And a depiction of man's vomits and war with himself.
It is death of course, and friendship.
He describes it absolutely incredible!
At the same time, he is also fun.
In the middle of everything when it is at its most, there will be a laugh or a song.
What Shakespeare writes should be performed in front of the audience.
Theater is popular again, because it is taken from antiquity.
Here comes all the strata of life.
Shakespeare mixes high and low, to satisfy everyone.
A solemn monologue can be mixed with a joke.
A recurring theme is death.
You know the famous scene from Hamlet?
"To be or not to be?"
It's about living or not living.
As many as 74 of Shakespeare's characters die on stage.